- The most important aspect of every project,
especially AI projects, is the objective.
In the case of AI,
this is about your algorithm's objective.
What is your goal and what do you want to accomplish?
It's important to know
that AI ultimately learns to achieve a certain objective.
Think for a moment.
What's your objective?
Your algorithms objective should ultimately ladder up
to your business goal, and as we discussed before,
when it comes to AI, the options are vast.
This is why it's necessary to start
with what you're trying to accomplish as a business,
and not with what is AI capable of doing?
For example, in industries that rely heavily on creativity
and novelty, you can use it to come up with new ideas.
You can generate personalized textbooks in education.
You can generate new levels in game design.
You can even create new clothing styles in fashion,
but in industries that rely heavily
on processes and workflows,
you can use it to automate tasks,
streamline decision-making,
and personalize a customer journey.
This can range
from B2B software companies that manage
complex backend flows to medical companies looking
to simplify their patient experience.
As we'll discuss later in this course,
AI can power those end-to-end workflows for you.
At LinkedIn, we often look at AI as the matchmaker,
helping connect job seekers with their dream companies,
or brands with their buyers, or connecting communities
of professionals looking to learn from each other.
Now, regenerative AI models, you can take that even further,
offering AI as a copilot for professionals
to help them accomplish their explorations,
all with the mission of connecting professionals
to make them more productive and successful.
In addition, a key part
of our objective is to ensure
we create a more equitable economic future
for every professional.
That's why equity is a big part
of how we define our algorithm's objective.
If you haven't made note of your business objective,
make sure you pause this video
and write it down before moving to the next one.
And don't try to get it perfect, just write a few ideas.
Start with what challenges are most important
for your business to solve over the next few years.
You can always revisit the objective later.
As we go through the course,
think of how the lessons
and takeaways connect back to your objective.