- The impact of AI on society
will be undoubtedly very large.
while society is still getting warmed up to the idea
of self-driving cars, imagine getting used to the idea
of AI-powered doctors or AI-powered psychologists.
It would also become very personal and intimate.
Imagining a dedicated AI model that runs across your phone,
your computer, your photo albums, your voicemail
and every piece of digital footprint you have.
Imagining its ability to understand how you think,
how you talk, and how you act.
Now, couple that with deep fake technologies
that can mimic your voice and image
with extraordinary precision.
As you can imagine, this concept goes well
beyond the metaverse of extending our identities online
to being able to mimic our identities,
at least based on what's possible today digitally.
This brings with it enormous societal challenges
that will continue for the foreseeable future.
This is probably the right time to mention
that as AI continues to evolve, we can also expect
regulators and governments to increase focus
on responsible AI development with new policies
and laws overseeing the use and applications of AI.
Throughout this course,
we discussed AI's extraordinary ability to extract
and generate insights and information from large data sets.
Basically, it can comprehend and then regenerate
all existing knowledge,
but what about creating completely new knowledge?
Can AI come up with new scientific ideas
or scientific hypotheses?
Imagine AI coming up with new answers or solutions
for some of the biggest scientific mysteries we have today,
such as what is dark matter and dark energy?
How does the brain create consciousness?
What is one's self?
What is the correct interpretation of quantum mechanics?
What causes Alzheimer's disease?
AI cannot answer these questions yet.
Currently, it only operates within existing knowledge,
but that can change, and AI can become better
at extracting and generating insights and informations,
enabling it to come up with new hypotheses or theories.
At that point, we're looking at a whole new frontier
for the human race.