- At this point, you should have a basic understanding
of how AI might become more integrated into your business.
But now let's talk about
how you bring your team along for the ride.
As a business leader,
you are in a unique position
to help drive positive change within your organization.
Think about how you can encourage your team
to embrace and lead with AI.
I'm a big believer that you can't manage
what you don't understand.
By demystifying this technology,
you can address any fears or hesitations
your team might have
and empower them to become ambassadors for innovation.
In the next section,
we'll learn about the limitations of AI today
and why it's important to keep
responsible AI principles in mind.
That will help you and your team
develop a more rounded perspective
of what's possible today and what they can expect next.
Remember, you and your team
don't have to be technology experts
but deepening your collective understanding of AI
will help you make more informed decisions moving forward.
Before we finish this section,
I have one more recommendation for you.
Given the novel nature of this technology
it can be extremely beneficial to empower your organization
to actively participate and experiment with new ideas.
For that purpose
I would propose you create
a lightweight playground or sandbox environment
to help your teams experiment with ideas
in a low cost, safe way
before they go and build a full plan for them.
The next big idea for your business
can come from anyone in your company.
So if you can foster a culture
of experimentation and innovation
while keeping responsible AI principles in mind,
you'll be well positioned to reap the benefits
of AI as it evolves.