- It's incredible to see people's reactions to
generative applications.
At first, people get really excited.
Wow, it could do this for me?
That this is something that is usually very dear
and near to their daily work.
But sometimes that excited tone
is replaced by a worrisome one
when they realize the impact it can have
on their daily work and responsibilities
and that's not surprising.
Today's AI can do anything,
from seamlessly automating your workflows,
to analyzing your financial situation,
to offering personalized advice
on enhancing your business model.
From writing speeches, to summarizing complex texts,
to generating videos, movies,
even creating new Broadway shows.
For writing code, understanding code,
reviewing somebody else's code,
finding security breaches in your code,
and even fixing them for you.
I can go on and on and on.
This list is endless and the potential is truly enormous.
One of the most powerful ways to think of AI
is to think of it as your co-pilot,
your incredible collaborator
or that personal genie you always wanted.
Imagine having an assistant,
extremely intelligent and capable, working alongside you
on everything you're trying to accomplish.
That assistant has been exhaustively trained
on all public knowledge available.
Every book, every piece of literature,
every artwork, and text that exists in the world.
It has developed superior comprehension
and generative skills.
And its ability to learn, understand, and communicate,
surpasses anything you have experienced before.
It doesn't know you yet, but it would if you let it.
Imagine a world
in which AI can take your business idea
and help make that a reality.
What would you like to accomplish with it?
Pause this video and take a few moments
to think about one thing you or your business could use help
with today and how this technology can help assist with it.
And when you're ready, click play to continue.
Now, if you're feeling unsure about how you
or your business can benefit from this technology,
don't worry about it.
This can feel overwhelming, but by the end of this course,
you'll have many ideas.
If you're feeling somewhat uncomfortable,
that's also expected.
This technology can feel very personal,
and when used incorrectly, it could lead to unintended even
dangerous outcomes.
If you already came up with many ideas, that's also
not surprising.
The implications for you and your company are vast.
Whether it's about transforming an internal process
or a product you have, every aspect of your work
can potentially get enhanced.
Keep in mind that failing to adopt AI in your business
can also potentially place you at a disadvantage.
As competitors will learn this new technology
and it'll start creating exponentially
better products than yours
with significantly higher productivity and lower costs.
That's why in this course we'll learn how to keep
up with this technology and reimagine your business
or endeavor with generative AI models.