- AI has the potential to impact
a wide range of processes and products
across a variety of industries.
Without a doubt, many of those implications
can be relevant for you and your company
from productivity and efficiency,
basically how can you do more with less using AI,
to product innovation, how can you take
your product experience to the next level.
When we think about productivity and efficiency,
workflow automation is a good place to start.
AI can help streamline tasks across the company.
These tasks do not have to be specific and basic.
In fact, they can be pretty complex.
Let's take reports as an example.
Using the right prompt in the workflow,
AI can play a key role in creating,
integrating, analyzing, and summarizing reports
into insights and action items,
not only saving time and resources,
but also reducing errors and inconsistencies.
Next, when coupled with automation,
AI can start facilitating that end to end experience.
In our customer service example,
imagine being able to automate the entire workflow
starting from answering routine customer inquiries,
then automatically logging tickets,
finally working towards resolving the inquiries,
and completely handling the back and forth for the customer.
That's pretty remarkable, right?
When you're able to combine tasks and workflows
within a self-directed production,
you can dramatically enhance
your organizational productivity.
This can be applied to many of your routine operations
from finance to marketing to sales
to product development.
And to make things even more powerful,
you can use AI to play a critical role
in enhancing your own data and analytics capabilities
by integrating data reports from multiple sources,
creating a new, more comprehensive data set,
generating synthetic data,
which can mimic the properties of real data
without exposing any sensitive information,
and summarizing large data sets,
making it easier to digest and understand the key findings.
Essentially, you can train AI with your specific workflow
and decision-making process
and incorporate it as the brain of your operation.
These capabilities are not only for internal processes.
If your product or service includes workflows,
like many B2B software companies,
you can then extend these capabilities
into your product to drive innovation.
You can start incorporating AI
across several dimensions in your product,
across all development cycle.
AI can explore the design specs for your product
and help identify potential gaps
or suggest new combinations or features
or functionalities for you.
Last, and potentially most important,
it could speed up innovation
by taking on some of the creative heavy lifting.
By modeling trends, patterns,
and relationships in data,
AI can generate new ideas and solutions
that otherwise would not be apparent.
This could be especially valuable
when it comes to rapid product development.
It could really help speed up time to market
for innovative new ideas.
With generative applications,
no creative process has to start with a blank slate.
You can jumpstart it easily
with your AI brainstorming partner.
Before you go to the next video,
take a moment to brainstorm specific ways
you can apply AI to your business.
Given the business objectives you outlined
for yourself before, consider areas
where you might be able to improve
productivity or efficiency
and how you can use AI to inspire product innovation.