- In AI, data matters a lot.
If you've been tracking AI for a while,
or took my previous course, you know the reason for it.
AI learns and trains itself with examples,
past examples and real-time examples,
and those data samples are the fuel
that helps AI achieve its objective.
The fuel analogy was real.
Several years ago, data was even coined as the new oil.
The more quality data you had,
the better the results you got,
the bigger the competitive mode you developed,
and the more successful you ultimately became as a company.
The latest AI models are challenging
that competitive advantage.
One of the most impressive aspects
of recent generative AI models
is that they're already trained
on the world's public knowledge.
And now that's accessible to everyone,
which will make it a commodity over time.
Recent developments also enable AI models
to create synthetic mock data,
or even learn without any data,
which is useful in cold start situations,
where it's difficult or impossible
to obtain examples of training data.
These developments lower the barriers to entry
for companies that otherwise would not be able to compete.
So if you are in this no data camp,
that's great news for you.
But what does it mean for businesses
that heavily rely on proprietary data
that is either owned or controlled exclusively by them?
Well, if that's you, it's time to rethink your strengths
as a business and extend your abilities
beyond data capabilities.
Data alone will not be sufficient.
That said, proprietary data still matters,
especially if you can fine-tune the model
towards a specific task.
Now, you might be asking, "What is fine-tuning,"
"and why is it important?"
AI models like GPT, which stands for
generative pretrained transformer,
are general purpose AI models,
which have a broader objective function
and are already trained on all public knowledge.
They know as much as possible,
and are designed to perform reasonably well in many tasks,
just like generalists.
ChatGPT, which is the conversational application of GPT,
is one example of these models,
but you can fine-tune these models
to be specialists in a specific area
by training them on unique examples you have.
And during this fine-tuning process,
the model will adjust its parameters to better fit your data
while still learning the knowledge
it has gained in the past.
This allows the model to become a specialist
in a specific area that you want it to learn,
while still being able to generate in a general way.
Imagine taking athletes and training them
to be distance runners, or weightlifters, or gymnasts.
You can, and probably should do the same
with your application.
Otherwise, your product will not be very different
than anybody else's.
You'll be relying on the same capability
everybody else is using.
Now, you might be thinking that fine-tuning is your answer
to maintaining some of your competitive advantage,
but it's important to know that creating a private instance
of your own fine-tune model can be very expensive
and difficult to maintain.
We'll talk more about that later
in the AI limitation sections of this course.