- Now, let's discuss the AI model. The algorithm.
This is the brain of the operation.
It defines how the model
will learn patterns and relationships within the data,
and then apply that knowledge
to perform an intellectual task.
In the case of generative models,
it uses the knowledge it has gained to create new content
in the form of images, text, video, audio, and more.
With recent developments in AI, we are now
experiencing a new foundational model
that sets the basis for many AI systems
that we'll use in the future.
A foundational model is considered a new paradigm
for building AI systems.
It becomes a starting point
for a wide range of downstream tasks.
Looking back at the categorical evolution of AI systems,
we started with the rule-based algorithms
and those made decisions
based on a set of explicit logical rules.
That later evolved to search and optimization algorithms,
that focused on efficiently exploring solution spaces
and finding the optimal results.
Think of a search engine.
Then, we had machine learning algorithms,
such as supervised, unsupervised,
and reinforcement learning,
which were used to analyze and classify data.
Those really paved the way for massive progress
in computer vision and natural language processing.
Machine learning then branched
into deep learning algorithms,
which became the state of the art technology
in image classification, object detection,
and natural language understanding.
GPT, the Generative Pre-trained Transform
we discussed before,
sets the ground for a new foundational model.
It is a large language model
that is trained on a massive amount of text data
and is able to generate new text in response to user input.
It is based on transformers,
which is a deep learning architecture
that was invented in 2017 and became very popular over time.
In my previous course, I mentioned this
as one of the most exciting developments in AI.
Transformers are a type of neural network
that uses a technique called self-attention
to identify what parts of an input, sets of an article,
are most essential,
focusing on the relevant parts and ignoring the rest.
This in turns helps the network better understand the input
and makes more accurate predictions.
Transformers are used in a variety
of natural language tasks,
from generating text based on input prompts,
think about ChatGPT, to summarizing or translating text
from one language to another with high accuracy.
For example, I recently used GPT
when I published a post in English
and did a translation to Hindi
and the result was incredible.
Instead of simply translating the words,
the model understood the intent of my post,
and then rewrote that in Hindi,
in the style of a native speaker.
I got many compliments for my Hindi.
Another recent foundational model is the diffusion model.
Diffusion models have emerged in recent years
as a powerful new approach to generative modeling.
Specifically, in the field of image generation.
They work by gradually transforming a starting image,
usually starting from random noise, into a target image,
like a photograph,
through a series of small, randomly determined steps.
Due to their ability to produce photorealistic images,
diffusion models have potential applications
in a wide range of domains.
For instance, they could be used
to accurately identify or classify objects in images,
restore images, and generate rich media
for use in many applications.
Lastly, another promising area of AI research
is called Reinforcement Learning from Human Feedback.
This approach uses signals from human evaluators,
such as upvotes or downvotes,
to improve the performance of an AI model.
By incorporating this feedback,
the model learns to adjust its decisions
based on how well they align with human expectations.
This approach can be particularly effective in domains
where it's difficult to define clear objective functions
for the model to optimize for.
For example, a social media moderation AI
might use reinforcement learning from human feedback
to better identify offensive or harmful content,
and then limit its spread on the platform.
Now, there's another very valuable tool
for refining AI models, which is called prompt engineering,
but the application of it goes far greater.
It's a whole new interaction model,
so let's learn about that next.