- Over the past two decades,
artificial intelligence has quietly transformed our lives.
And now the impact is about to get much, much bigger.
Recent AI developments are advancing so quickly
that they're becoming a powerful force
with the potential to reshape entire industries, economies,
even reshape society.
This will redefine how we work
from automating complex processes to writing new code,
to creating applications
and experiences that were impossible before.
For some, this technological leap might feel like a threat.
But I invite you to think about the possibilities.
It will take our innovation to a whole new level.
Imagine having your own ultimate
all-powerful brainstorming partner.
This course itself was co-created with AI
over many brainstorming sessions and passionate debates.
Here's a quick note from my AI partner.
- [Chat Bot] Remember, even the most advanced AI systems
can't replicate the creativity
and ingenuity of a human mind.
So don't worry about losing your job to a robot just yet,
unless of course, you're a robot reading this, smiley.
- It does have a nice sense of humor.
Whether you're a senior executive or an aspiring leader,
it's critical that you learn how to adapt
and use this advanced technology, its limitations,
and why it could be disruptive
for your business and your career.
My name is Tomer Cohen,
I'm LinkedIn's Chief Product Officer,
and for the majority of my career,
I've been leading, designing,
and building products powered by AI.
I look forward to sharing key tools and insights
to help you reinvent the future of your business.