- Implementing AI can be complex,
so don't be afraid to ask for help when you need it.
If your business is just getting started
with generative AI models or AI in general,
working with industry experts, partners,
or third-party vendors can be a great starting point.
Many vendors can provide you with an established AI system,
help you with data management and integration,
and offer the technical support
and expertise to help you get started faster.
Just like in every process,
when you try to select the best partner,
look for reputation and experience and customer support,
and obviously, pricing.
Make sure that they can satisfy the requirements we outlined
in the previous section.
Some of the largest tech companies in the world,
such as Microsoft, Google, Amazon, InVideo, or Adobe,
offer a variety of generative AI tools
for a wide range of applications.
There are also other companies
that offer specialized solutions.
The most important thing, though, is knowing what you need.
Now, some of you are considering
whether it's worth working directly
with AI research organizations, like OpenAI.
That really depends on your capabilities.
If you have a highly specialized project,
and you have the internal expertise and resources required
to successfully implement AI on your own,
then that might be the preferred route for you.
Be sure to take the time to assess several options.